corelaboratory.abbott 2019-04-11

# Privacy Policy | Abbott U.S.

Abbott Laboratories Privacy Policy US Residents Only

This Policy applies to residents of the United States. If you are a resident of another country, please [click here](http://www.abbott.com/global-sites.html) for applicable information.

This Privacy Policy explains how we handle the personal information that you provide to us on Web sites controlled by Abbott Laboratories (including its subsidiaries and affiliates) which link to this Privacy Policy (referred to as "Abbott Web sites") and other information collected through your use of Abbott Web sites. This Privacy Policy does not apply to personal information collected from you offline, to Abbott Web sites that do not link to this Privacy Policy, to residents of countries other than the United States, or to third-party Web sites to which Abbott Web sites may link. Your use of Abbott Web sites, which link to this Privacy Policy is subject to this Privacy Policy and the [Terms of Use](http://www.abbott.com/online-terms-and-conditions.html).

Please read this Privacy Policy before using Abbott Web sites or submitting personal information to us.

How does this Privacy Policy define "personal information"?  
"Personal information" means information that identifies you or could reasonably be used to identify you and which is submitted to and/or collected by Abbott Web sites and maintained by Abbott in an accessible form.  Examples of personal information include your name, your postal address and your telephone number.

How does Abbott collect information online?  
Abbott collects information in two ways:

  * Personal Information You Submit: Abbott collects personal information that you enter into data fields on Abbott Web sites.  For example, you may submit your name, postal address, e-mail address, and/or other information in order to receive information about various subjects, register for Abbott programs, contact Abbott customer service, or respond to Abbott surveys. To protect your privacy, you should not provide Abbott with any information that is not specifically requested.
  * Passive Collection of Non-identified Information:
    * Abbott Web sites may collect information about your visits to Abbott Web sites without you actively submitting such information.  Non-identified information may be collected by Abbott and our website/advertising partners using various technologies, such as cookies, Internet tags, and web beacons. Your Internet browser automatically transmits to Abbott and our website/advertising partners some of this Non-identified information, such as the URL of the Web site you just visited and the browser version your computer is operating.  Passive information collection technologies can make your use of Abbott Web sites easier by allowing Abbott and our website/advertising partners to provide better service, customize sites based on consumer preferences, learn which advertisements and features bring users to our Abbott Web sites, compile statistics, analyze trends, and otherwise administer and improve Abbott Web sites. For example, some of our Abbott Web sites use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses cookies to analyze use patterns and may collect information about your use of the website, including your IP address. More information on Google Analytics can be found here: www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/. Certain features of Abbott Web sites may not work without use of passive information collection technologies. Information collected by these technologies cannot be used to identity you without additional identifiable information.
    * Abbott participates in the Adobe Marketing Cloud Device Co-op to better understand how you use our website and apps across the various devices you use, and to deliver tailored promotions. [Learn more](https://cross-device-privacy.adobe.com/) about how Adobe does this.

Does Abbott engage in Retargeting and Interest-Based Advertising?  
Abbott uses third party advertising companies to place ads on other websites. These companies may use Non-identified information (discussed immediately above) about your visits to Abbott Web sites and other websites in order to measure advertising effectiveness and to provide advertisements about our goods and services that may be of interest to you. Like most advertisers, we place advertisements where we think they will be most relevant to customers. One way we do so is by allowing network advertising companies with whom we work to place their own cookies when an individual visits Abbott Web sites. This enables the network advertising company to recognize individuals who have previously visited Abbott Web sites. When the individual visits a third-party web site on which that network advertising company has purchased ad space, the advertising company can then recognize the individual’s interest in our products and services and deliver one of our advertisements.

Some of our websites use two Google Analytics Advertising Display Features, which collect information through cookies: Remarketing with Google Analytics and Demographics and Interests reporting. If you would like to opt-out of having your data used by these cookies, please use the Google Analytics opt-out available here: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/.

The Digital Advertising Alliance maintains a web site where consumers can opt out from receiving interest-based advertising from some or all of the network advertising companies participating in the program (www.AboutAds.info/choices).

In what circumstances might Abbott collect and use personal information?  
Abbott will use the personal information you provide through Abbott Web sites to respond to your questions and to provide you with efficient customer service. After you have entered personal information into a form or data field on an Abbott Web site, Abbott may use certain technologies to allow that Web site to "remember" your personal preferences, such as sections of that Web site that you visit frequently and, if you choose, your user ID. We may also use this personal information for other business purposes, such as to offer you the opportunity to receive notices regarding Abbott’s products or services, to invite you to participate in surveys about our products, or to notify you about special promotions.

Does Abbott consolidate personal information?  
Abbott may consolidate the personal information of customers who use Abbott Web sites. We use this information to help us better design Abbott Web sites and Abbott products, to communicate information to you, to enhance our marketing and research activities, and to facilitate other business functions.

What choices do I have about how Abbott collects and uses personal information about me?  
You may always limit the amount and type of personal information that Abbott receives about you by choosing not to enter any personal information into forms or data fields on Abbott Web sites. Some of our online services can only be provided to you if you provide us with appropriate personal information. Other parts of Abbott Web sites may ask whether you wish to opt out or opt into our contact lists for offers, promotions and additional services that may be of interest to you.

You may also be provided with preference questions or preference boxes allowing you to indicate that you do not want Abbott Web sites to use tracking technologies, such as cookies, to "remember" your personal information, such as user IDs or mailing addresses, on return visits. However, Abbott Web sites that use tracking technologies to collect Non-identified information do not generally provide you with the ability to opt out of the tracking technologies. Some Internet browsers allow you to limit or disable the use of tracking technologies that collect Non-identified information.

Who will have access to personal information about me?  
Personal information can be accessed by a restricted number of Abbott employees, by certain companies with which Abbott may conduct joint programs, and by individuals and entities with whom Abbott contracts to carry out business activities for Abbott. We train our employees about the importance of privacy and how to handle and manage customer data appropriately and securely. Also, it is Abbott’s practice to notify you if you are registering for a program which is conducted in conjunction with another company that may require access to your personal information. In addition, Abbott’s practice is to require its contractors to keep your personal information confidential and to use personal information only to perform functions for Abbott.

Does Abbott share personal information with third parties?  
As a general rule, Abbott does not share your personal information with third parties, unless it is necessary to conduct a joint program or to carry out a program or activity through a contractor. However, if Abbott sells one of its product lines or divisions, your personal information may be transferred to the buyer so that the buyer can continue to provide you with information and services. If Abbott provides your personal information to individuals and entities which assist us with our business activities, it is Abbott’s practice to require those individuals and entities to keep your personal information confidential and to use your personal information only to perform functions for Abbott. Abbott reserves the right to disclose your personal information to respond to authorized information requests from government authorities, to address national security situations, or when otherwise required by law.

How does Abbott secure personal information?  
It is Abbott’s practice to secure each web page that collects personal information; however, the confidentiality of personal information transmitted over the Internet cannot be guaranteed. We urge you to exercise caution when transmitting personal information over the Internet, especially personal information related to your health. Abbott cannot guarantee that unauthorized third parties will not gain access to your personal information; therefore, when submitting personal information to Abbott Web sites, you must weigh both the benefits and the risks. In addition, Abbott Web sites covered by this Privacy Policy will display a warning whenever you link to a Web site that is not controlled by Abbott or subject to an Abbott privacy policy; you should check the privacy policies of such third-party Web sites before submitting personal information.

Abbott has policies that provide for the proper use and protection of Social Security numbers obtained in the course of doing business with Abbott.  Abbott’s policies require that Social Security numbers be appropriately secured to avoid loss, misuse or unauthorized access of Social Security numbers. Unlike this Privacy Policy, which applies only to on-line personal information, Abbott’s policies governing Social Security numbers apply to both on-line and off-line collection and use of Social Security numbers.

How does Abbott protect the privacy of children?  
Abbott does not knowingly collect or use any personal information from children (we define "children" as minors younger than 13) on Abbott Web sites. We do not knowingly allow children to order our products, communicate with us, or use any of our online services. If you are a parent and become aware that your child has provided us with information, please contact us using one of the methods specified below, and we will work with you to address this issue.

How may I correct personal information or delete it from current customer records?  
You may request to remove your personal information from our current customer records or to amend your personal information. Please notify us of your wishes by contacting us in one of the ways specified below. For our record keeping purposes, we will retain certain personal information you submit in conjunction with commercial transactions.

How can I contact Abbott?  
If you have questions about the use, amendment, or deletion of personal information that you have provided to us, or if you would like to opt out of future communications from an Abbott business or a particular Abbott program, please contact us by clicking on the "Contact Us" link on the Web site you are visiting or by e-mailing us at [webmaster@abbott.com](mailto:webmaster@abbott.com). Alternatively, you may send a letter to the following address:

Abbott Laboratories  
Attention: Public Affairs, Department 383  
100 Abbott Park Road  
Abbott Park, IL 60064-6048

In all communications to Abbott, please include the e–mail address used for registration (if applicable), the Web site address or the specific Abbott program to which you provided personal information, and a detailed explanation of your request. If you would like to delete or amend your personal information and are contacting us by e-mail, please put "Deletion Request" or "Amendment Request", as applicable, in the subject line of the e-mail. We will do our best to respond to all reasonable requests in a timely manner.

How will I know whether Abbott has updated this policy?  
Abbott reserves the right to amend this Privacy Policy without prior notice to reflect technological advancements, legal and regulatory changes and good business practices. If Abbott changes its privacy practices, a new Privacy Policy will reflect those changes and the effective date of the revised Privacy Policy will be set forth in this paragraph. This Privacy Policy was last updated on July 13, 2018 and is effective as of that date.
